proporta.co.uk 2017-08-25

# Privacy Policy | Proporta

## Privacy and Data Security  
  
---  
  
     \- What we do with the stuff we know  
     \- Proporta's Privacy commitment  
     \- Consent  
     \- Information about you  
     \- How we use your personal data  
     \- Cookies   
            What  are cookies?   
            How does Proporta use cookies?   
            How do I turn cookies off?  
            Other Useful links  
     \- Data over the internet   
     \- How we protect information  
     \- How you can help us protect your information  
     \- Further information   
     \- How to unsubscribe  
     \- Changes to privacy policy  
  
### What we do with the stuff we know  
  
At Proporta, we recognise that privacy and security is a major concern. We have therefore set out below the guidelines we use for protecting your personal information. Please read this Privacy Policy carefully and check it periodically since it may change from time to time.  
  
### Proporta's Privacy commitment  
  
Proporta is committed to safeguarding your privacy online. We will only collect, store and use your personal information for specific purposes. We use your personal information to support and enhance our relationship with you. We only share your personal information in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998 and other applicable laws. You may contact Proporta at any time with any privacy questions or concerns and to see the personal information you have given us and request correction.  
  
### Consent  
  
Your use of the proporta.com website, group gifting application and any disclosure of personal information via the website signifies your consent to us collecting and using personal information about you in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

Back to top of page   
  
### Information about you  
  
When a customer registers at proporta.co.uk we ask for information such as your name, email address, postal address, and contact details, and then we keep a record of this information. All this is necessary so we can recognise you as a registered customer, pass on the correct details with your order, and ensure that you are happy with the service you receive.

We keep a record of any email correspondence you send us, so we can track any problems or concerns you've had. 

We'll also ask you questions at registration, and from time to time by email, that will give us information that will be used to improve your experience of shopping at proporta.com. You do not have to answer these questions, but if you do we can communicate with you in a more relevant way.

If you would like to revise the information you have provided to us, or feel that what we currently have on record is incorrect, you may update the information by emailing: [hello@proporta.com](mailto:hello@proporta.com)

Back to top of page   
  
### How we use your personal data  
  
All the information we collect via our website or through correspondence with you is used to operate and improve the service we offer you and to personalise our service. We are committed to using your personal information only for:

1\. Planning and managing proporta.com's business activities, including analysis of customers' shopping habits, product and style preferences.  
2\. Technical administration of our website.  
3\. Research.  
4\. Providing you with information about the services we offer.   
5\. Letting you know about offers and news from proporta.com.  
6\. To verify details of your payment method or credit card account. 

These are the circumstances in which we may share some of your data with others:  
1\. In the unlikely event that our business assets are ever sold to or purchased by another company (our data records are part of our business). You will receive notice of any such event and we will use our reasonable endeavours to ensure that the new combined entity will follow the practices disclosed in this Privacy Policy.   
2\. To outside research companies whom we may ask to contact you directly for your opinions on our service, and our partners' products and services (in which case we provide them with only the information they need to perform their function).  
3\. If we are requested by the police or a regulatory or government authority investigating illegal activities to provide information concerning your activities whilst using the network we shall do so. 

Back to top of page   
  
### Cookies  
  
### \- What  are cookies?  
  
'Cookies' are really small text files that are stored by the browser (e.g. Internet Explorer or Firefox) on your computer or mobile phone. All websites use them to store such things as user preferences. Think of cookies as being a "memory" of the website, enabling it to recognise a user and respond appropriately. At Proporta we use cookies to keep track of what you have in your basket, and to remember you when you return to our site.

To order products on proporta.com, you do need to have cookies enabled. If you don't wish to enable cookies, you'll still be able to browse the site and use it for research purposes. Most web browsers have cookies enabled, but see Managing cookies for help to turn them on should you need to.

Cookies cannot hurt your computer. We don't store personally identifiable information such as credit card details in the cookies we create, but we do use encrypted information gathered from them to help improve your experience of the site. For example, to determine relevant related products to show you when you're browsing. We're giving you this information to ensure compliance with recent EU legislation, and to make sure we're honest and clear about your privacy when using our website.

Back to top of page   
  
### \- How does Proporta use cookies?  
  
A visit to a page on proporta.com may generate the following types of cookie:  
  
Language and Currency preference cookies  
  
Website analytics cookies  
  
Registration / Login cookies  
  
Social Sharing cookies  
  
Advertising Cookies  
  
###  Language and Currency preference cookies  
  
These cookies are used to work out what country you are in from information supplied by your browser when it requests a web page. This cookie is completely anonymous, and is only used to help target content - such as whether you see our UK our Italian home page - and advertising.  
  
###  Website analytics cookies  
  
Each time a user visits our website, web analytics software provided by Google Analytics generates an anonymous analytics cookie. We use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookies) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to report how our ad impressions, other uses of ad services, and interactions with these ad impressions and ad services are related to visits to your site. We also use data from Google's Interest-based advertising or 3rd-party audience data (such as age, gender and interests) with Google Analytics.

These cookies cannot be used to identify individuals; they are used for statistical purposes only. If you are logged in, we will also know the details you gave to us for this, such as username and email address. If you wish to opt out of these cookies, follow this link:<http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout>  
  
###  Registration / Login cookies  
  
If you register or login with Proporta, we generate a cookie to signal whether you are signed in or not. Our servers use these cookies to work out which account you are signed in with.  
  
###  Social Sharing cookies  
  
When you visit a Product page and 'share' a product using one of the social media icons, we generate a cookie to allow us to measure social activity on our site. These cookies are anonymous - they store information about the content you are browsing, but not about who you are.

We believe that setting this cookie enhances your internet experience. However, if you prefer that we do not collect this non-personally identifiable information, visit   http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out#.T7856RQS06I where we will place an opt-out cookie on your computer.  
  
###  Advertising Cookies  
  
Proporta uses cookies to help with its targeted advertising. Proporta uses Remarketing with Google Analytics to advertise online. Third-party vendors, including Google, show our ads on sites across the Internet. Proporta and third-party vendors use first-party cookies (such as the Google Analytics cookie) and third-party cookies (such as the DoubleClick cookie) together to inform, optimize, and serve ads based on someone's past visits to your website.

These cookies are anonymous - they store information about the content you are browsing, but not about who you are.

We also set anonymous cookies on certain other sites that we advertise on. If you receive one of those cookies, we may then use it to identify you (anonymously) as having visited that site if you later visit the Proporta website and purchase something.  
  
### How do I turn cookies off?  

All internet browsers like Internet Explorer or Safari allow you to change your cookies and turn them on or off. These settings are normally found in the 'options' or 'preferences' menu of your browser. The following links may be helpful, otherwise try the 'Help' option in your browser.

Cookie settings in Internet Explorer  
Cookie settings in Firefox  
Cookie settings in Chrome  
Cookie settings in Safari  
To turn off third party cookies set by advertisers, visit Your Online Choices website.  
  
### Other Useful links  
  
If you want to read up even more on cookies and how they are used on the Internet, you can also visit:

For information specifically about privacy issues and Internet advertising, try: [Youronlinechoices](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) If you have any other questions about Proporta's use of cookies, please email us at [hello@proporta.com](mailto:hello@proporta.com).

Back to top of page   
  
### Data over the internet  
  
The internet is a global network, so it is possible for your data to travel internationally, which may include places outside the European Union. If you visit or shop at proporta.com, you're agreeing and authorising us to process data in this way. 

Back to top of page   
  
### How we protect information  
  
You acknowledge that the Internet is not a 100% secure medium for communication and, accordingly, we cannot guarantee the security of any information you send to us (or we send to you) via the Internet. We are not responsible for any damages which you, or others, may suffer as a result of the loss of confidentiality of such information.

We take every precaution to protect your information. To this end all personal information stored by us is kept on a server in a secure environment. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job are granted access to personally identifiable information.

Back to top of page   
  
### How you can help us protect your information  
  
Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online in non-protected environments - for example on message boards, through email, or in chat areas - that information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Also remember to close your browser window when you have finished your work. This is to ensure that others cannot access your personal information and correspondence if you share a computer with someone else or are using a computer in a public place like a library or Internet café. We cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

Back to top of page   
  
### Further information  
  
If you have questions about your personal data or our privacy policy, please contact us at [hello@proporta.com](mailto:hello@proporta.com). 

To see all the information we have about you, and to correct any inaccuracies, please write to us at: proporta.com, Unit 3, Woodingdean Business Park, Sea View Way, Brighton, East Sussex, BN2 6NX 

Back to top of page   
  
### How to unsubscribe  
  
If you no longer wish to receive any further email messages, post or other communications from us or you no longer wish to be contacted by other companies who you permitted us to provide your details to then please email [hello@proporta.com](mailto:hello@proporta.com) or change your account settings accordingly.

Back to top of page   
  
### Changes to privacy policy  
  
We reserve the right to change our privacy policy, whilst of course keeping it within all relevant legislation and guidelines. We will do all we can to ensure that these pages show the most up to date information at all times, and may notify you of such changes by uploading the revised privacy policy on the proporta.com website.

Back to top of page
